Finding Aid for Bureau of Alumni Relations (University of Michigan) records, 1929-1951
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Bureau of Alumni Relations (University of Michigan) records 1929-1951
University of Michigan. Bureau of Alumni Relations.
8736 Bimu H5 2
Records, 1929-1951,of the Bureau of Alumni Relations of the University of Michigan. Include correspondence and other papers of director Wilfred B. Shaw concerning education by radio, adult education, the Alumni Club Lecture Series, the University of Michigan Press, the American Alumni Council, the Centennial of the University in 1937, university history, the Ann Arbor Art Association, the Ann Arbor Rotary Club, the Michigan Historical Commission, and the Alumni Association of the University.
10 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received from the Bureau of Alumni Relations (donor no. 212 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
The Bureau of Alumni Relations was established in 1929 to foster alumni relations through adult education programs for the alumni. Wilfred B. Shaw was the director from 1919 to 195. He initiated the publication of bulletins for the alumni. Under his direction, the bureau issued reading lists, arranged lectures, served as the center for distribution of university news releases, and conducted the "Alumni University," a week of campus classes in early summer.
The records are organized into six series: Correspondence with Alumni Associations at Other Schools, 1929-1938; Papers; Other Correspondence, 1929-1935; Wilfred B. Shaw Topical Files; University of Michigan Centennial materials, 1937; and Topical Files.
In addition to Shaw's correspondence relating to bureau activities and the American Alumni Council, there are articles on the development of alumni education programs in other institutions, the broader adult education movement in the United States, and evaluations of ongoing projects at the university and their relationships to the Extension Service.
Subjects:
Adult education.; American Alumni Council.; Ann Arbor Art Association.; Michigan Historical Commission.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. Alumni Association.; University of Michigan--Anniversaries, etc.; University of Michigan--History.; University of Michigan. Press.; Radio broadcasting--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ann Arbor Rotary Club.; Shaw, Wilfred Byron, 1881-1959.
- Correspondence with Alumni Associations at other schools 1929-1938
  - A through O (Box 1)
  - P through Z (Box 2)
- Papers
  - Education by Radio 1931-1935 (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan Press 1931-1935 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Alumni Activities, circa 1929 (Box 2)
  - American Association for Adult Education 1929-1939 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Club Lecture Series 1931-1937 (Box 2)
  - American Alumni Council 1929-1936 (Box 3)
  - Adult Education (Box 3)
  - Alumni Reading Lists 1931-1934 (Box 3)
  - Speeches by William B. Shaw (Box 3)
  - Movie Education and University Films (Box 3)
  - University History Materials (Box 3)
- Other Correspondence 1929-1935
  - Correspondence with Carnegie Corporation 1929-1935 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with American Association of University Women 1930-1932 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence with the American Library Association 1929-1931 (Box 3)
- Wilfred B. Shaw Topical Files
  - A (Box 4)
  - A (cont.) (Box 5)
  - A (cont.) (Box 6)
  - B through O (Box 7)
  - P through Z (Box 8)
- University of Michigan Centennial
  - Miscellaneous materials 1937 (Box 9)
- Topical Files
  - Committee on the Institute of American Culture and Institutions (Box 10)
  - Shaw Etchings (Box 10)
  - Ann Arbor Art Association (Box 10)
  - Rotary Club (Box 10)
  - Vassar College Alumni Conference 1929 (Box 10)
  - Alumnae Council (Box 10)
  - Michigan Historical Commission (Box 10)
  - Michigan Interscholastic Press Association Conference 1939 (Box 10)
  - Committee on Special Needs (Box 10)
  - New Education Fellowship (Box 10)
  - National Youth Administration (Box 10)
  - Publicity Correspondence (Box 10)
  - American Alumni Council 1951
    - Honorary Alumni (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous Subjects (Box 10)